A Full-Stack Web/Mobile Developer

Shanghai, China (+86) 15216761725 pilixiaoxuanfeng@gmail.com http://pinkyjie.com

ABOUT

My name is Wenbo Jie, I am a honest and diligent person who has strong passion and ability to learn new things. Through four years of mathematics learning(bachelor degree), as well as more than two years of computer research(master degree), I have a deep understanding of computer science. After graduation, I have been worked in Internet industry as a software engineer for more than two years, I have got in touch with almost the full project development process. Specifically, I am experienced in web application development & mobile app development. I am also familiar with cloud computing.

EDUCATION

Yangzhou University Mathematics(Bachelor of Science)

Yangzhou, Jiangsu — 2005.9-2009.6

East China University of Science & Technology Applied Computer (Master of Engineering)

Shanghai — 2009.9-2012.3

- First-class Scholarship Every Year
- Third prize of Mathematical Contest in Modeling
- Publication in Neurocomputing
- Publication in <u>Knowledge-Based Systems</u>

EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer(Web/Mobile Development), Zealion Technology

Shanghai — 2011.6-2012.9

Zealion is a startup company that makes Web apps and Electric Checkin app for exhibitions. As a main programmer, I have been almost touched the full process of project, not only web front-end/backend and mobile development, but also more non-development job, such as requirement analysis, user behavior research, user experience optimization, etc. These make me becoming a full-stack developer who has special understanding of development.

Software Engineer(Cloud Computing), Samsung Electronics(China) R&D Center

Shanghai — 2012.12-present

Samsung is the one of top 500 companies, as a engineer, what I learned most from here is its standard software engineering. I have a big improvement in my coding style, which makes my code more strong and more conformable with the coding conventions. In addition, I also step into Cloud Computing field from here.

SKILL

- Front-end
- Javascript[80%]
- HTML5[60%]
- o CSS3[40%]
- Flash[20%]
- Backend
- Python[70%]
- Java[50%]
- Node/Ruby/PHP[30%]
- Mobile
- Non-native[60%]
- Android/iOS[20%]
- Cloud
- o AWS[30%]
- Cloudstack[30%]

Familiar Libraries: ¡Query Backbone.js Marionette.js Underscore.js Bootstrap Yeoman Grunt.js SASS/Compass web.py Flask Rails Express.js Sencha Touch

Familiar Toolchains: GIT/SVN Sublime-text Ubuntu/Mac

LANGUAGE

• English: CET4[566] CET6[566] TOEIC[725]

PROJECT

• Cloud Resilience(Front-end)

[jQuery.js Underscore.js Bootstrap SVG Font-Awesome web.py MongoDB Scalr AWS API Cloudstack API]

A Cloud Resilience System help to simulate disasters on your cloud infrastructure. Inspired by Netflix's Chao

A Cloud Resilience System help to simulate disasters on your cloud infrastructure. Inspired by Netflix's Chaos Monkey project, do network/system/storage/power disaster simulations which aim to make your cloud app more robust. This system aims to improve the robustness of Samsung's S-Vocie.

• Fitting Room(Main Programmer)

[jQuery Bootstrap PHP MySQL Flash FLARTookit Papervision3D]

A web app on Taobao Open Platform for virtually trying clothes using camera or photo. This App won the Top 5 in Taobao App Contest in 2012.

• Fitting Room Admin(Main Programmer)

[jQuery Bootstrap KnockOut.js Mustache.js Underscore.js Node.js MongoDB]

A web admin app for Taobao sellers who use the app Fitting Room. Sellers can use it to add/view/edit/delete their product showed in Fitting Room app.

• Wish Tree(Web)

[Rapheal.js Node.js Socket.io MySQL]

An interactive multiple device app for annual meeting. User can use iPad to input some words and take a photo, than the wish card will be immediately showed on the big screen with animation.

• Checkin for iPad(Main Programmer)

[Objective-C PHP MySQL C#]

An Electric Checkin app for iPad, guest can use this app to quickly find his name and print his ID card for meeting.

Photo Booth(demo)(Main Programmer)

[C++ OpenCV OpenNI Kinect]

A copycatting Mac app that implements the functionality of Photo Booth provided by Mac OS X, which can replace your camera video background with other things in real-time. OpenCV and Kinect help to recognize the background and do image processing issues.

• Cloth Gallery(demo)(Main Programmer)

[Objective-C FFmpeg]

An iPad app for clothing manufacturer to better exhibit their clothes product with smooth user experience.

• Trister(My Project)[https://github.com/PinkyJie/Trister/]

[Sencha Touch Sass Flask Tweepy Shell AppFog]

A simple mobile web Twitter client implemented by pure HTML/CSS/JS.

• Twitter2Sina(My Project)[https://github.com/PinkyJie/Twitter2Sina/]

[Python Tweepy GAE]

An auto-synchronizing tool hosted on Google App Engine which synchronizes your tweet from Twitter to Sina Weibo.

• iFrameExtractor(My Project)[https://github.com/PinkyJie/iFrameExtractor/]

[Objective-C FFmpeg]

A demo iPhone app using FFmpeg library to extract frames. This project is forked from lajos/iFrameExtractor and updated for iOS 5.1 on Mac OS 10.7.4 and FFmpeg 0.11.1. The pull-request is accepted by the original author.

• PinkyBlocker(My Project)[https://github.com/PinkyJie/PinkyBlocker/]

A simple firewall app for android phones to help you block spam SNS and unwanted call. It has many options to help you customize the blocking rule.

• Blog(My Project)[https://github.com/PinkyJie/pinkyjie.github.com/]

[Jekyll-Bootstrap Font-Awesome]

My personal blog website is built with jekyll-bootstrap and hosted on Github Pages. I have insisted on writing blogs for more than 3 years.

• LiangziDown(My Project)[https://github.com/PinkyJie/LiangziDown]
[Chrome SAE]

A Chrome extension which helps you download Liangzihendao real time statistics data with just one click.

INTEREST

Skating Travelling

REFERENCE

- More Detailed version of this Resume: http://pinkyjie.com/resume
- My Blog: http://pinkyjie.com
- My Twitter: https://twitter.com/PinkyJieMy Github: https://github.com/PinkyJie
- My StackOverflow: https://stackoverflow.com/users/689948/pinkyjie